DS students, welcome to GIT Smashers
Today's video we are going to explain Integrity Constraints in Database
You can see that you created a database
There are a lot of tables in the database
Now you are going to add data in the tables
Obviously, why do you create a database in the action?
So that database can organize the proper data properly
Later on, we can use it to access something
So we need to do some research, to delete it
So whenever we talk about the database
In this database, when I want to add data
I am also adding an unshunt
I have picked up all the tables and put it in the file
No, there should be no rules there
So that the data in the actual database
is supposed to be integral
What is the meaning of the integral?
There is a value, there should be a uniqueness
I am saying that the value of X is 100
There is a value of X in the database
There is a third person's value
So there is a third person's value
So there is a uniqueness
I am not an Integrity
So I am not an Integrity
So what is the actual value?
What is the meaning of these Integrity Constraints?
Rules
The set of rules
Before adding data in the database
Before inserting it
If we insert it
Then if we update it later on
We delete it
So there is nothing in our hearts
There must be some set of rules
And those rules
They maintain the actual database
So that the data is made in accuracy
Consistency
Reliability
This is actually a concept
You can say
That you maintain the quality of the data
Helps the Integrity Constraints
It is very simple
Note it here
Because many times
Directly
Let us ask this
Types of Integrity Constraints
So first of all
Let us come to you
Domain Constraints
Domain in actual
Means
Domain is related to the attributes
You will add a lot of attributes in your table
Like employee's table
Or student's table
So you have to say
You have to add some student's or employee's age
Its name will be added
Or let us suppose you have to add a mobile number in it
So in this way
You will add multiple attributes
And you say
Sir, can I add anything in this?
No
So you have to say
Sometimes when we make attributes
Then we have to mention the data type
Like we have to mention the integer type of data
Means we have to decide the domain
That it will take the data of the integer type
You have to add it
That it will take the correct type of data
So string type of data
You have to say
That it can take the data of the integer type
That this is the data type
But people
Or they say
When the data is entering in the database
What is the value of the entry operator
The value of the entry is minus five
How much is the student's age is minus five
Or how much is the employee's age is zero
Is this possible?
So here this constant is boiling
As if the domain is boiling
So this thing keeps the domain constant
Let me give a simple example
Like by using the check constraint
How can you stop it?
How can you set the check constraint
Up to the age
You have set the check
The age must be greater than zero
So what will happen?
If you add a minus five
You can't add it
It can't be added
It will click
It will run on the submit
It will run on the run
If you add zero
Like by using a simple example
You can say
Sir, I added the mobile
And there is a note
What is happening there?
1,2,3
9,8,7
That means
Obviously the mobile
You know that it is a 10 digit
So if someone has a rate
If someone has a rate
So then
You can also add a check constraint
Check that there is a length
The length of the mobile number must be what?
It must be equal to 10
You can also add a constraint
It has a set of rules
The later ones in the SQL
They implement the SQL
But here you have to understand
What is the meaning of this constraint?
The data that you are adding
It should be valued
It should be added to something
Then you have your integrity
Integrity constraint
It is totally related to the primary
It is said that the primary
It should be equal to a primary
So that the uniqueness
And it should be not null
So the primary
It should be equal to
It is unique and not null
You cannot repeat the data
And it cannot be null
So at least one constraint
One attribute is
It should not be null
So what do you do to make the primary
And also
If you check the playlist of the DBMS
So lecture number 8
It is said that the primary
And the entire form of the primary
So you have to repeat it
So you understood the story
Then it is said that the referential integrity constraint
It is totally related to the
Foreign
That means
There are two tables
One table is master table
One table is a child table
And whatever I am adding in the parent table
That is the same in the child table
That is the same in the parent table
And you are adding the data in the child
So there are several referential integrity
And it is violating
To save it
So what is the foreign
How do you maintain it
I have already told you
In the description
You will be on the link in the description
I have told you the lecture number
8, 9, 10
In the playlist of the DBMS
Where you will find the full story of the foreign
Primary
And in the end
What is your key constraint
This is related to the unique
Unique
There are many attributes
But what is the key constraint
That in your table
It should be a unique attribute
It is like a half card number
Unique
License number
Unique phone number
E-mail ID
But it should be a unique attribute
And what is unique
It is related to Candidate
Candidate is the property
What is unique
That is why
If you summarize this topic
What is the meaning of this topic
You have to understand this topic
What is Candidate
What is Primary
And what is Foreign
And that is the only thing
In lecture number 8, Candidate
In lecture number 9, Primary
And in lecture number 10, Foreign
So this is why
To do these topics
In the end, E-R model
Relational jabra-relational model
You will get a key in all the topics
But now if you do this
You will understand the future
So this is why
Please note it and think